<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Matthew Crews</title>
    <link>/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Matthew Crews</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Advisor</title>
      <link>/services/project-advisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/project-advisor/</guid>
      <description>You have a team ready to build and deploy an inventory optimization tool, but you need someone to ensure that the tool doesn&amp;rsquo;t bury the business by making incorrect recommendations.
Inventory optimization tools regularly increase profits by over 10% while reduce carrying costs over 20%. For them to be successful though, you need to ensure that the data is good, and the assumptions are correct. When you bring me on to advise your team, I can ensure that your tool will give you the returns you are looking for and will not cause you to make poor buying decisions that drag down your profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Call</title>
      <link>/services/strategy-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/strategy-call/</guid>
      <description>You are ready to transform your planning tools with Mathematical Programming but are unsure where to start. Let&amp;rsquo;s take an hour to figure out precisely what kind of problem you have and the best tools for solving it. Sometimes all you need is someone who&amp;rsquo;s seen the problem before to help you get unstuck.
You will come away with a clear picture of what the best approaches are for solving your problem and know the kind of returns you can expect if you use Mathematical Programming to solve your planning problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
