<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Matthew Crews</title>
    <link>/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Matthew Crews</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Custom Solution</title>
      <link>/services/custom-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/custom-solution/</guid>
      <description>You are sick and tired manually calculating purchase order quantities and are ready get your time back while maximizing your profit
To start, you and I will spend 1-hour discussing where your inventory management is at and see if we are a good fit for one another. If we agree to move forward, I will then meet with your stakeholders and any technical staff that I would need support from. This meeting takes up to 2 hours for me to get input from your team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Advisor</title>
      <link>/services/project-advisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/project-advisor/</guid>
      <description>You have a team ready to build and deploy an inventory optimization tool, but you need someone to ensure that the tool doesn&amp;rsquo;t bury the business by making incorrect recommendations.
Inventory optimization tools regularly increase profits by over 10% while reduce carrying costs over 20%. For them to be successful though, you need to ensure that the data is good, and the assumptions are correct. When you bring me on to advise your team, I can ensure that your tool will give you the returns you are looking for and will not cause you to make poor buying decisions that drag down your profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueprint</title>
      <link>/services/blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/blueprint/</guid>
      <description>You want to reduce your carrying costs by 25%, you have developers ready to build the tool, you just don&amp;rsquo;t know what to build.
How It Works We start with a one-hour call to dig into your pain points around managing your inventory. If we decide that a Blueprint is the right thing for you, we will spend two weeks putting together a detailed architecture and process flow for an inventory optimization tool for your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Call</title>
      <link>/services/strategy-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/strategy-call/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re struggling to get a handle on your inventory, and you need someone with experience to help you figure out where to even start.
You book a 1-hour call with me, and we will figure out what your biggest struggles are and what your critical next step is. Sometimes all you need is someone who&amp;rsquo;s seen the problem before to help you get unstuck. I guarantee you will have actionable information to start transforming how you manage inventory or your money back.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
